One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
This sucks...
参ったな
My body... It's burning up.
熱い…　体が
I guess... I'm still alive.
まだ　生きてた
But... for how much longer...?
でも　このまま死ぬのかな
There's no one here.
誰もいねえ
An abandoned ship, huh?
乗り捨てられた廃船か
Scrap wood... Scrap iron...
廃材…　鉄くず…
This place makes me feel... right at home.
俺にはずいぶん 落ち着く場所だ
First things first, I've gotta do something... about this useless body!
まず　この動かねえ体を 何とかしねえと…
Did you hear?
知ってるかい？
Tom's violent apprentice, Cutty Flam, is dead.
凶暴なトムの弟子 カティ･フラムは死んだそうだ
He was hit by the sea train.
海列車にひかれて…
Iceburg...
アイスバーグ…
you can do it.
おめえならやれる
Tom was the world's greatest shipwright, and you were his finest apprentice.
世界一の船大工トムの 一番弟子なんら
I'm sure you can do it...
きっとやれる
I'm sure...
きっと…
Miss Kokoro, let's grab a drink one of these days...
ココロさん そのうち一緒に飲もう
We'll blow off some steam.
楽しい酒を
Yeah.
ああ
Mr. Tom...
トムさん…
please watch me.
見ててくれ
I'll carry on your will.
俺はあなたの意志を継ぐ
I'll make sure to protect...
守ってみせるさ
everything!
全てを
This town...
この町も
and these blueprints as well!
この設計図も
Mr. Iceburg, you have a guest.
アイスバーグさん　お客様が
He said you would know him if I mentioned "Cutty Flam."
“カティ･フラムと言えば分かる”と
Franky?
フランキー！？
Shall I show him in?
お通ししますか？
No.
いや…
Turn him away.
追い返せ
You've got a roundabout way of meeting people.
ずいぶん回りくどい会い方をするんだな
Well... anyway, what's up with that strange-looking body?
ンマー　てめえしかし 何だその珍プレーな体形は
Put a sock in it!
うるせえ！
My body was totaled, so I had to rebuild it with scrap metal to survive!
体中使い物にならなくなったんで 鉄くずで改造して生き延びたんだ
More importantly,
それよりてめえ！
I heard your company's been building ships for the World Government!
おめえの会社じゃ世界政府の船を 請け負ってるそうじゃねえか！
I'm not gonna keep quiet while you help those bastards!
俺は許さねえぞ！ 政府に手を貸すようなマネ
After they took Mr. Tom and–
あいつらはトムさんを…
Have you forgotten who made the weapons that caused that incident?!
そのきっかけとなった凶器は 誰が作ったもんなんだ！
I'm sure you have a lot of things that you want to say to me...
今の俺に対して おめえも言いてえこともあるだろうが
but don't think that I've forgiven you in the past four years.
この４年の歳月で 俺がお前を許したと思うな
After what happened,
あんなことがあってよく
I can't believe you have the nerve to show your face!
俺の前に堂々と面を出せたもんだ
What'd you say?!
何だと！
I was certain you were dead.
お前のことは 完全に死んだと思っていた
That's what the government reported.
政府はそう報告してきたからな
Mr. Tom might have forgiven you,
たとえ　トムさんが許しても
but I'll never be able to!
俺はお前を許す気はねえ
H-Hey, what the hell?!
お…　おい！
Aren't these the blueprints we saw for that ancient weapon?!
何だよこりゃ あの時の古代兵器の設計図じゃ…
Don't use the name Cutty Flam ever again.
この先カティ･フラムの名は捨てろ
Since the government couldn't get them from Mr. Tom,
トムさんからこいつを 引き出せなかった政府に
it's only a matter of time before they come for me.
俺が狙われるのも時間の問題だ
Take them and leave the island, Franky.
こいつを持ってこの島を出ろ　フランキー
Leave the island?
この島を？
Cutty Flam from Tom's Workers is dead.
トムズワーカーズのカティ･フラムは死んだ
As long as you don't use that name, they can't connect us.
お前がそれを名乗らねえかぎり 俺とお前がつながることはない
Leave the island with those blueprints and their trail goes cold for good.
その上に島を出ちまえば 設計図の行方は闇へ消える
H-Hold on a sec! What happens when they show up and you've got zilch?!
ちょっちょっと待て！ 設計図を持ってねえおめえがあいつらに狙われたらどうなる！
I've said my piece.
俺の用件はこれだけだ
Hold on! Iceburg!
お…　おい！ちょっ　アイスバーグ！
This may be farewell.
もう会うこともねえかもな
Hey! Wait!
おい！待てよ！
Do you wanna end up like Mr. Tom?
おめえ トムさんと同じ目に遭いてえのか？
Keep the blueprints with you!
設計図はお前が持ってろ！
If your life is in danger, you can just hand 'em over!
万が一命の危機が迫ったら こんなもんくれてやれ！
Hell, if that's not an option, torch 'em right in front of their faces!
渡したくなきゃ あいつらの目の前で燃やしたっていい
If you were me, would you do that?
お前が俺ならそうしたか？
Mr. Tom achieved so much,
あれだけの偉業を成したトムさんが
and he threw it all away to protect those blueprints.
全てを捨てて未来へつないだ設計図だ
If there's even the slightest risk that Nico Robin can revive the ancient weapon,
少なくともニコ･ロビンという女が 実在する兵器を復活させる危険がある以上
the world needs those blueprints to fight back.
それは抵抗勢力として この世に必要なものだ
Even if I continue to keep them with me...
たとえこのまま俺が持っていたとしても
I'd sooner die... than hand the government those blueprints!
俺は殺されようとも　政府には渡さん
You sure about this?
いいのか？
I might build the thing.
俺はこいつを作るかもしれねえぞ
Can you really trust me?
俺を信用していいのか？
Doesn't my giving them to you answer that question?
それを渡したことで 答えにはならねえか？
We never change, huh?
俺たちはいつまでも変わらねえな
We yell at each other whenever we meet.
顔を突き合わせりゃどなり合って
I still won't forgive you...
この先も俺はお前を許さねえし
and maybe you feel the same way, but...
お前も　そうかもしれねえが
Franky...
フランキー
I'm...
てめえ
really...
ホントに…
glad...
生きてて
you're alive.
よかったな
Hold on, Dumburg!
待てよ！バカバーグ！
I'm not leaving this island!
俺はこの島を出ていかねえからな！
I do what I want!
俺は　俺のやりたいようにやる
I would never do what you tell me to, even if it kills me!
てめえの言うことなんか 死んでも聞かねえからな！
Never!
絶対に！
Flunky, you moron!
このバカンキーが！
We heard Tom was indeed a skilled shipwright,
我々の聞いているトムという男は
but he was also a dangerous, unruly fishman with monstrous strength.
腕は確かだが 凶暴で手に負えない怪力の魚人
When we asked around, the townspeople only gave vague answers.
町の人間に聞いても口を濁すばかりだ
It must be tough as an apprentice to defend such a man.
そんな男をかばわなきゃならない弟子も
Right, Cutty Flam?
大変だな　カティ･フラム
I'm too tired to take that bait.
言い返す気力も湧かねえ
You government agents are all trash!
てめえら政府の人間は みんなクソだ！
What?! Hey, hey...
うえっ　おいおい
Back then, over 100 citizens, including marines and officials,
当時　このウォーターセブンで 海兵とその他役人に
were severely injured here in Water Seven.
100人を超える重傷者を出した
The culprit behind it was you.
その犯人がお前だ
You had committed a grave crime against the World Government,
世界政府にそれだけのことをした罪は重いが
but since you were confirmed dead in the sea train accident on that very day,
その日のうちに　海列車の事故で 死亡確認されたために
no charges could be pressed.
罪は無効となっていた
But now, we'll finally take you to Enies Lobby as a criminal.
改めて犯罪者として お前をエニエス･ロビーへ連行しよう
You can take your time there answering our questions...
そこでゆっくり答えてくれればいい
about the whereabouts of the blueprints for Pluton.
プルトンの設計図の在りかについて
Blueno.
ブルーノ
Yeah. It just connected.
ああ ちょうどつながったところだ
When we reported this case to our chief, he wished to speak with you immediately.
うちの長官にこの件を報告したら すぐにでもお前と話したいと言うもんでな
Your chief?
長官？
Please go ahead, Chief.
どうぞ長官
Ouch!
どわちゃっ
It's hot! It's hot! It's hot! I spilled my coffee!
熱っ熱っ熱っ… あー　コーヒーこぼした！ああっ
Dammit! Stupid coffee!
ちくしょう！こんなコーヒー！
What the heck?
何なんだ？
Are you there...
そこにいるのか？
Cutty Flam?
カティ･フラム
It's been a while.
久しぶりだな
I never imagined you had survived...
まさかあれで生きていたとはな
It's hard to believe, but I'm happy to hear it.
信じられねえが うれしいニュースだ
These past eight years, every time my scars hurt,
この８年傷が痛むたびに
I was tormented by an anger that I couldn't take out on anyone...
俺はぶつけようのない怒りに さいなまれて生きてきた
because the criminal who disfigured me croaked.
自分を傷つけた犯人が 死んじまったからさ
Who the hell are you?
誰だ？おめえは
You don't remember me?
覚えてねえか？
I'm the man from Cipher Pol No. 5 who personally apprehended Tom's Workers
８年前　サイファーポールナンバー５で 司法船襲撃現行犯
for attacking the judicial ship eight years ago!
トムズワーカーズを逮捕した男さ
You bastard! Spanda!
てめえ　スパンダ！？
With an "m"! It's "Spandam" with an "m"!
“ム”だ！“ム”！スパンダム！
I'll be very much looking forward to your arrival at Enies Lobby.
エニエス･ロビーでお前の到着を心待ちにしているぞ
Now, men!
さあお前ら
Quit dillydallying and bring that criminal here already!
その犯罪者をさっさとここへ連れてこい！
Ouch! It's hot! It's hot! It's hot!
うわ～っ！あちゃちゃちゃっ…
Stupid lamp!
何だこのランプ！
Roger.
了解
Ow, ow, ow...!
いてててっ
Dammit! Let me go, you jackass!
ちくしょう　放せこの～
Let's move.
行くぞ
Not another step, scumbags!
おい待てお前ら！
Drop him, now!
そいつを放せー！
My apologies.
ごめんなさい
Hey! Is that swagger just for show?
うおい！おめえの輝きは一瞬か！
If memory serves, you're one of the Straw Hats, correct?
お前確か　麦わらの仲間じゃな
What?
えっ…
This isn't working! The wind is too strong!
ダメだ！風に負けちまう
It's not going out!
全然消えねえ！
Anyone inside will be done for if this keeps up!
まだ中にいたら これじゃもう助からねえぞ
Mr. Iceburg!
アイスバーグさん
Mr. Paulie!
パウリーさん！
Nami...!
ナミ…
This is bad...
大変だ
I have to...
早く
treat her...
治療
right... away...
して…　やんなきゃ…
Treat them immediately! Those burns are serious!
早く手当てを！すごいヤケドだ！
Hey, what about this reindeer?!
おいっ！このトナカイどうする？
Him, too! He saved their lives!
そいつもだ　命の恩人だぞ！
Y-You're right. Hey! Give me a hand!
そうだな おーい！手を貸してくれ！
Ah, man.
あ～あ
He got his ass kicked.
やられちまった
So, in short, you're no longer part of the Straw Hats,
つまり麦わらの一味は抜けたが
but you're still a dastardly pirate, huh?
まだ海賊はやめておらんのじゃな
In that case, we'll apprehend you as well.
海賊ならば連れていく
Kalifa!
カリファ
Roger.
ええ
As for this ship...
それとこの船…
you haven't scrapped it yet?
まだ処分しておらなんだか
Watch it! Don't you dare lay a finger on her!
おいてめえ！そいつに触るなよ
Wh-What are you doing?!
な…　何してんだよおい
Hey, are you listening?!
聞いてんのか！？
Although our professions were a cover, we're still accomplished shipwrights.
仮の姿とはいえわしらは この町ではれっきとした船大工
When we tell you a ship is no good, you should pipe down and listen.
ダメなものはダメだと 聞き入れてほしいもんじゃ
So what?! Just leave her alone! She's not even your ship!
それがどうした！放っとけよ お前の船じゃねえんだから！
This lets out the water, right?
これで水が出せるんじゃな
Wait! Don't do anything stupid! Hey!
待て！バカなマネやめろよ！おい！
Hey! Stop it!
おい　やめてくれ！
Don't worry.
大丈夫
I'll carry you guys for a little bit longer.
もう少しみんなを運んであげる
Merry!
メリーッ！
Get back! It's gonna collapse!
離れろ！崩れるぞー！
Dammit!
ちくしょう！
Run, dumbass!
バカ野郎！逃げろ！
Dammit! Isn't there anything we can do?!
クッソ～　何とかなんねえのか
Mr. Iceburg has regained consciousness!
アイスバーグさんの意識が戻った！
Really?! That's amazing!
そうか　よかった！
What a relief! He's okay!
よかった無事で
Mr. Iceburg!
アイスバーグさん！
It's all thanks to that reindeer!
あのトナカイのおかげだ
But... I heard he's the Straw Hats' pet.
だがありゃ麦わらたちのペットらしいぞ
Hey! This one, too!
おいっこっちもだ！
The woman woke up!
女が目を覚ました
Wh-What now? Should we make her cough up the Straw Hats' whereabouts?
ど…　どうする？ すぐに麦わらの居場所を吐かせるか？
It feels weird to interrogate an injured lady.
だけどひでえケガだぜ　女だし…
That's–
そんなこと…
Mr. Iceburg, you shouldn't be up!
ちょっ…　アイスバーグさんまだ動いちゃ…
You guys...
お前ら
give us some room.
俺たちから少し離れてろ
I want to talk to this woman alone.
この女と２人で　話をしてえ
What could the two of them be talking about?
何だろうな　２人で話って
Beats me.
さあ？
Ow! What'd you do that for?!
痛えっ！何すんだ！
Quit standing around!
ボケッとしてんじゃねえ！
Mr. Lucci and the others could still be inside!
まだ中にルッチさんたちが いるかもしんねえんだぞ
Give us a hand, you idiots!
こっちを手伝えバカ野郎！
Oh, that's right. C'mon!
あっそうだった　おい
Yeah, our bad!
ああ　すまねえ！
Well...
ンマー
First, I must apologize.
まずは　申し訳なかった
We falsely accused you of a crime. I'll set the record straight later.
お前たちに妙なぬれぎぬを着せた 誤解は後で解いておく
I want to talk about Nico Robin.
話はニコ･ロビンのことだ
Do you know something?!
何か知ってるの？
Did she start acting strange upon your arrival to this town?
この町へ来て あの女の様子は変わったか？
Yes, it was very abrupt.
ええ　急に
Right after we got to town, she suddenly disappeared.
町へ出たあと　突然いなくなって
By this morning, she was already the suspect of your attempted assassination.
今日の朝には　あなたの 暗殺未遂の犯人になっていて
When our crew finally tracked her down...
仲間がやっとロビンを捜し当てたら
she told us she wouldn't be returning.
もう あたしたちの所へは戻らないって
We didn't understand what was happening,
あたしたちは何が何だか分からなくて
so we came here tonight to ask her once more why she's leaving the ship.
今夜もう一度　直接ロビンに船を下りる理由を 聞くためにここへ来たのよ
To make my wish come true...
私の願いをかなえるためよ
A wish that can never come true if I stay with you...
あなたたちと一緒にいても 決してかなわない夢を
What is this wish that can't come true if she stays?
あたしたちと一緒にいちゃ かなわない夢って何？
I'll tell you what I know.
俺の知ってることを話そう
It was probably when you lost sight of Nico Robin the first time.
おそらく　お前たちが最初に ニコ･ロビンを見失った時だろうな
I'm with CP9.
ＣＰ９です
The government's operation was already in progress.
既に政府の作戦は始まっていたんだ
There is, of course, a reason for that woman's actions.
あの女の行動に もちろん理由はある
But... before I tell you that,
だが　そのことを話す前に
you should know that both Nico Robin and I have a means to revive an ancient weapon
俺とニコ･ロビンは世界を滅ぼすほどの 古代兵器を呼び起こすすべを
that could destroy the world.
持ってると思って聞け
Destroy the world?
世界を？
That's right.
そうだ
Our plan hit a snag.
作戦に障害が発生した
Everyone, come to the bedroom immediately.
全員すぐに寝室へ
Don't shoot Iceburg yet.
アイスバーグはまだ撃つな
You get it now, Nico Robin?
分かったかニコ･ロビン
The blueprints you guys were after are fakes.
お前らの狙った設計図は　偽もんだ
Even if it gets me killed, I won't give those blueprints to the government!
俺は　たとえ殺されても 設計図は政府には渡さねえ
But if you're sniffing around the poneglyphs and helping the government,
なのに一方で　お前がポーネグリフを嗅ぎ回り 政府にも力を貸すってんなら
then I have to stop you right here, right now!
俺はお前をここで止めなきゃならねえ
I'm not seeking the poneglyphs in order to bring the weapon back.
何も私は兵器復活のために ポーネグリフを求めているわけじゃないわ
I just...
ただ
want to know the history.
歴史を知りたくて
That's no excuse!
そんな言い分に意味はねえ！
I told you.
俺は言ったぞ
Again and again...
何度も　何度も…
Whether you intend harm or not,
たとえお前にその意志がなくても
weapons don't care who they hurt...
凶器は誰かを傷つける
even if it's someone you love!
それがお前にとって大切な人間でもだ
That which hurts people doesn't necessarily have malicious intent.
人を傷つけるものに 必ずしも悪意があるとはかぎらない
If your simple curiosity about the history of the world would lead to its destruction,
歴史を知りたいというただの興味が 世界を滅ぼす結果を招くなら
you should die here and now, Nico Robin!
今お前はここで死ぬべきだニコ･ロビン
You still wish to pursue that history after seeing what befell those devils of Ohara?!
オハラの悪魔たちの運命を目の当たりにして まだ歴史を追いかけてえのか！
And what would you know about Ohara?!
あなたがオハラの何を知ってるのよ！
You have no idea...
世界政府の手で
how much the World Government has ruined my life!
私の人生がどれほど狂わされたのかも知らないで
If you hate them so much, why are you helping them?!
それほど嫌う政府に じゃあなぜ加担する！？
Because no matter the cost, I have a wish I must fulfill.
全てを捨てても かなえたい夢があるからよ
There were two conditions that CP9 forced on me in this town.
この町で　ＣＰ９が 私に突きつけてきた条件は２つ
The first was to pin your assassination on the Straw Hats.
１つは　暗殺の罪を 麦わらの一味に着せること
The second was to surrender myself to the government and obey all their orders.
もう１つはその後政府に 私の身を預け　従うこと
If you do that, you'll die, too.
そうなればお前の命もないぞ
After running for twenty years, why take a deal like that now?
20年逃げ延びた女が なぜそんな条件をのむ？
On this single occasion,
ＣＰ９は
CP9 has been given authorization to exercise a buster call against the Straw Hats.
麦わらの一味に対し　たった一度だけ バスターコールの発動を許可されていたの
A buster call?
バスターコール？
It's a priority call to Marine Headquarters
海軍本部の中将５人と
to send five vice admirals and ten battleships to one place.
軍艦10隻を一点に招集させる緊急命令
Once you're the target of such overwhelming military might,
その国家戦争クラスの軍事力の標的にされたら
there's absolutely zero chance of survival.
後にはもう何も残らない
This authority is normally held by the three admirals
本来それは　海軍の中でも３人の大将と
and the fleet admiral at the head of the Marines.
海軍トップの元帥にしか使えない権限
But this time,
だけど　今回ＣＰ９は
thanks to Admiral Aokiji,
大将青雉を介して
CP9 was authorized to utilize it just this once.
一度だけそれを発動できる権利を与えられていた
If I hadn't cooperated, a buster call would have befallen us.
条件をのまなければ 私たちにバスターコールがかかる
As soon as I heard the name Aokiji, I gave up.
青雉のその名を聞いた時に観念したわ
These last twenty years,
私が今まで20年
I never had an issue running away because I had nothing to protect...
どんな状況でも逃げ延びてこられたのは 守るものがなかったから
Because I could betray others and use them as my shield.
人を裏切り　盾にできたから
But now...
でももう
I can't just abandon them.
今の私には本当に　それができない
The life I once discarded...
一度捨てた命も
The heart that I lost...
失った心も
The dreams I thought were dead... They kept bringing them back to me.
途絶えた夢も みんなすくい上げてくれる
I found friends...
こんな私を信じてくれる
who truly believe in me.
仲間ができた
Then...
じゃあ
what is your wish?
お前の願いってのは…
That the six Straw Hat pirates, excluding myself, be allowed to leave the island safely!
私を除く麦わらの一味の６人が 無事にこの島を出航すること
You'd revive the weapon for that?!
そのためなら兵器を呼び起こし
You don't care what happens to the world?!
世界がどうなろうと構わねえってえのか！
I don't!
構わない
Enough of this nonsense!
バカな考えはやめろ！
I couldn't pull the trigger.
俺は引き金を引けなかった
Of all the people...
事もあろうに
Over the lives of everyone in this world...
全世界に生きる 全ての人間の命よりあの女は
She chose to save the six of you.
お前たち６人の命を選んだ
It was for us...
あたしたちのため…
Now that they'll likely steal the weapon's blueprints anyway,
俺のほうの兵器の設計図も奪われそうな今
I don't have much room to talk, I guess.
俺にあの女を責める権利はねえが…
Hey! What's wrong?!
おい！どうした
What a relief...
よかった
So Robin...
ロビンはじゃあ
didn't betray us after all!
あたしたちを裏切ったんじゃないんだ
I've got to get everyone together pronto and let them know! Thanks, Mr. Iceburg!
早くみんなを集めて知らせなきゃ ありがとアイスバーグさん！
Hold on! You were all beaten soundly!
待て！麦わらたちもやられちまって
What do you think you can do now?!
今更何をしようってんだ
Now?!
今更ですって？
It starts now!
今からよ！
Luffy and the others are fine. It'll take more than that to keep them down.
ルフィたちなら大丈夫 あのくらいじゃやられない
We're going to get Robin back!
これからロビンを取り返すのよ
People waver when faced with uncertainty.
迷えば誰でも弱くなるもの
Once they know she needs help, they won't stop until she's safe!
助けていいんだと分かった時の あいつらの強さに限度なんてないんだから
Chopper!
チョッパー！
Chopper! Wake up! We have to find everyone!
チョッパー起きて　みんなを捜すのよ！
Chopper! Hey, wake up!
チョッパー　ねえ起きて
– Hey, hey, he's seriously injured...
おいおい　そいつはすげえ重傷で…
Wake up! Chopper!
起きなさい！チョッパー
Chopper...
チョッパー
Go join Luffy and the others and tell them everything that just happened.
お前ルフィたちと合流して 今あったこと全部話してこい
Don't leave out a single word.
一言一句漏らさずにな
What about you?
サンジは？
We'll part ways here for a bit.
俺は少し別行動をとる
Well, don't worry. I won't do anything reckless.
まあ心配すんな ムチャはしねえから
What's the matter?
どうした？
Do you think...
ロビンは
Robin hates us now?
俺たちが嫌いになったのかな
Chopper...
チョッパー
Remember this one thing:
１つ覚えておけ
When a woman lies...
女のウソは
a real man forgives her.
許すのが男だ
For the final train to Enies Lobby departing at eleven,
午後11時発 エニエス･ロビー行き最終便
please board from the second floor lobby due to the raised water level.
水位上昇中につき ご乗船は２階ロビーよりお願いいたします
Hey, let's sneak a peak!
よし　見にいこう
Yeah!
ああ
Since this involves a secret operation, you're prohibited from seeing who boards.
極秘作戦が絡んでるため 乗るとこ見るの禁止
– Rats!
ちぇ～っ
We've been pursuing you for twenty years.
20年も追われ続けた女が
I'm surprised you finally gave up.
よく観念したもんだ
Bingo.
ビンゴ